<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home on Urbanek.io</title>
    <link>https://www.urbanek.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Home on Urbanek.io</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 22 Jan 2021 15:01:08 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.urbanek.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://www.urbanek.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.urbanek.io/about/</guid>
      <description>I am, and ever will be, a white-socks, pocket-protector, nerdy engineer — born under the second law of thermodynamics, steeped in steam tables, in love with free-body diagrams, transformed by Laplace, and propelled by compressible flow.
&amp;hellip;
Engineering helped create a world in which no injustice could be hidden.
— Neil Armstrong
    Take what you want and leave the rest, just like a salad bar.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2019 Subaru Outback Map Update</title>
      <link>https://www.urbanek.io/post/subaru-map-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jan 2021 15:01:08 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.urbanek.io/post/subaru-map-update/</guid>
      <description>tl;dr  Download files using Map Downloader tool available at Subaru-Maps. Do not write the image to removable media using the tool, just download the update.  .chunk files are placed in C:\Users\&amp;lt;user&amp;gt;\Map Downloader\&amp;lt;random&amp;gt;   Merge and extract .chunk files using Expand-MapDownloadData PowerShell function  PS&amp;gt; . .\Expand-MapdownloadData.ps1 #dot-source defined function into PowerShell session PS&amp;gt; Expand-MapDownloadData -InputPath &amp;quot;C:\path\to\chunk&amp;quot; -OutputPath &amp;quot;C:\path\to\extraction\destination&amp;quot;   Copy extracted files (the update folder and everything inside) to root of NTFS formatted file system on removable drive With car turned off, connect USB removable drive to car USB port, then start car.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hugo — Lightbox Shortcode</title>
      <link>https://www.urbanek.io/post/hugo-lightbox-shortcode/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 May 2020 15:01:08 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.urbanek.io/post/hugo-lightbox-shortcode/</guid>
      <description>What A pure CSS lightbox — no JavaScript, turned into a Hugo {{&amp;lt; figure-lightbox &amp;gt;}} shortcode suitable to be used anywhere the built-in {{&amp;lt; figure &amp;gt;}} shortcode would be used.
Hugobiographical name1 Victor (-Marie) 1802-1885 French poet, novelist, and dramatist2 open-source static website generator written in Golanglightboxnoun1 JavaScript library by Lokesh Dhakar to display images and videos by filling the screen, and dimming the rest of the page2 any technique to display images and videos by filling the screen, and dimming the rest of the page, named in homage to the original JavaScript libraryshortcodenoun1 mini-templates (snippets) of code and markup that can be called within Hugo content files, commonly to augment the limitations of native MarkdownSeeing is Believing  &amp;lt;profound Yoda quote — violate subject-verb-object order, it will&amp;gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Generation Loss — Part 2</title>
      <link>https://www.urbanek.io/post/generation-loss-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 May 2020 22:15:08 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.urbanek.io/post/generation-loss-part-2/</guid>
      <description>Generation Loss — Part 1 Generation Loss — Part 2  Digital or Analog  How would you explain the differences between analog and digital systems to another engineer?
 Digital means 0&amp;rsquo;s and 1&amp;rsquo;s, right? Perhaps to the layperson, but there is far more to the story. Most helpful to think about how information is represented, moved around, and stored.
Generally:
 When representing the physical world, analog systems try (unsuccessfully) to be exact representations of a source phenomenon by mimicking without [much] manipulation in the middle.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Generation Loss — Part 1</title>
      <link>https://www.urbanek.io/post/generation-loss-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 May 2020 21:42:08 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.urbanek.io/post/generation-loss-part-1/</guid>
      <description>Generation Loss — Part 1 Generation Loss — Part 2  Two Techies Walk into a Bar One has their credentials revoked
Some time ago, prior to the COVID-19 social-distancing and safer-at-home orders, I was enjoying a beer with a fellow technology professional when something was said which caused my eyes to squint, head reposition, and settle in to a profoundly dumbfounded gaze:
 &amp;ldquo;&amp;hellip;kind of like when you copy a file and the copied data is not exact&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cautionary Tale — Continental Express Flight 2574</title>
      <link>https://www.urbanek.io/post/cautionary-tale-flight-2574/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Mar 2020 22:42:08 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.urbanek.io/post/cautionary-tale-flight-2574/</guid>
      <description>A cautionary tale of how imprecise language, along with its well-known accomplice latent safety culture, killed 14 people on September 11th, 1991.
Post is a follow up to Engineering Culture - Use Precise Language.
Image: Embraer EMB 120 Brasilia aircraft
 September 10, 1991 Overnight maintenance is scheduled to replace left and right de-ice boots on the horizontal stabilizer (part of the tail) of an Embraer EMB 120 Brasilia.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Engineering Culture — Use Precise Language</title>
      <link>https://www.urbanek.io/post/engineering-culture-use-precise-language/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Feb 2020 19:42:08 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.urbanek.io/post/engineering-culture-use-precise-language/</guid>
      <description>Language and culture are intimately related. Human communication is arguably one of the most complex negotiations in the known Universe (citation needed).
A principal factor in assessing an organization&amp;rsquo;s engineering culture is reviewing how engineering resources communicate, both verbally and in writing.
Regardless of engineering field, any technical discipline that interfaces with humanity (very close to my personal definition of engineering) finds itself communicating ideas, operations, limitations, concerns, and recommendations with other engineers, scientists, technicians, and customers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Agenda Time Planning</title>
      <link>https://www.urbanek.io/post/agenda-time-planning/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2020 12:25:40 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.urbanek.io/post/agenda-time-planning/</guid>
      <description>Head shot
 How hard can it be to plan a day The technology behind spitballing an agenda taking into account start times and duration should be easy. It wasn&amp;rsquo;t (at least for me and the 0 DDG searches I performed to investigate).
&amp;ldquo;Go ahead&amp;hellip; waste my day.&amp;rdquo; Below is the normal sequence of time wasting events:
 Flesh out agenda with start times in Excel, text editor, OneNote, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interview Fundies: Longest Prefix Match</title>
      <link>https://www.urbanek.io/post/interview-fundies-longest-prefix-match/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2020 23:14:48 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.urbanek.io/post/interview-fundies-longest-prefix-match/</guid>
      <description>Next Year&amp;rsquo;s Gartner MQ Leader in Enterprise Network Security
 Given Given the following simplified IPv4 route table:
Network Netmask Gateway------------ ------------- -----------0.0.0.0 0.0.0.0 172.16.1.1010.0.0.0 255.0.0.0 172.16.1.2010.0.0.0 255.255.255.0 172.16.1.3010.128.0.0 255.252.0.0 172.16.1.4010.128.0.0 255.255.0.0 172.16.1.5010.128.132.0 255.255.254.0 172.16.1.60 Question   To reach 8.8.8.8 what gateway will be chosen? To reach 10.128.0.10 what gateway will be chosen? To reach 10.128.134.52 what gateway will be chosen?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>They Call Her LINA</title>
      <link>https://www.urbanek.io/post/they-call-her-lina/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2020 21:11:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.urbanek.io/post/they-call-her-lina/</guid>
      <description>She&amp;rsquo;s in there somewhere&amp;hellip;
 R.I.P. ASA
firepower [fahyuh r-pou-er]pun1 foreshadowing at its finest2 tragic ironyPeer | review | needed. | Nah. | Already done.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>